In the history of horse racing, few horses have captured the affection of the British public like Red Rum.
在赛马史上，很少有马能像红朗姆这样赢得英国公众的喜爱。
Today, three decades after his retirement, he is still one of the best-known and most beloved racehorses of all time.
如今，红朗姆退役已有三十年，它依然是有史以来最知名、最受喜爱的赛马之一。
Red Rum was passed around to several owners before being purchased for Noel Le Mare.
红朗姆曾在好几位马主之间转手，后来才有人替诺埃尔·勒马雷把它买了下来。
The agent who made the purchase was the now-legendary horse trainer Donald “Ginger” McCain.
出面买下它的代理人，是如今已成传奇的驯马师唐纳德·“金杰”·麦凯恩。
It wasn’t apparent at the time, but Red Rum had a serious bone disease in his foot.
当时还看不出来，但红朗姆的蹄部患有一种严重的骨病。
For many horses (and many trainers) this would mean the end of a racing career before it even began.
对许多马（以及许多驯马师）来说，这就意味着赛马生涯甚至还没开始就宣告结束。
For Ginger and Red Rum, though, it was just an obstacle to greatness that had to be overcome.
不过，对金杰和红朗姆来说，这只是通往卓越之路上一道必须克服的障碍。
Red Rum’s true talent came out in steeplechases.
红朗姆真正的天赋在障碍赛马中显露了出来。
His power, speed and jumping ability carried him to his first Grand National title in 1973.
红朗姆的力量、速度和跳跃能力，助它在1973年首次夺得全国障碍赛马大赛冠军。
The very next year, Red Rum returned to take his second title.
紧接着的第二年，红朗姆重返赛场，夺得了第二个冠军。
He was the first horse to take successive firsts since Reynoldstown in 1935–1936.
它是继雷诺兹敦在1935年和1936年蝉联冠军之后，第一匹连续夺冠的马。
Red Rum’s spirit and grace had already begun to charm the legions of Grand National fans.
红朗姆的斗志和优雅风范此时已开始让全国障碍赛马大赛的大批赛迷为之着迷。
In the following two years, Red Rum lost out on the title, coming in second both times.
在随后的两年里，红朗姆与冠军失之交臂，两次都屈居第二。
When he returned in 1977 to try again, he was largely regarded as past his prime.
1977年它重返赛场再度一搏时，人们大多认为它已经过了巅峰期。
He was 12 years old and not expected to place highly.
当时它已12岁，人们并不指望它能名列前茅。
He surprised sporting fans around the world when he came in a remarkable 25 lengths ahead of the nearest horse, taking his third Grand National win.
它以领先第二名25个马身的惊人优势冲过终点，第三次夺得全国障碍赛马大赛冠军，令世界各地的体育迷大吃一惊。
To this day, Red Rum’s third win is known as one of the greatest moments in horse racing history.
时至今日，红朗姆的第三次夺冠仍被公认为赛马史上最伟大的时刻之一。
Red Rum was headed for the Grand National once again in 1978 but suffered an injury in one of his heels shortly before the race.
1978年，红朗姆本要再次出征全国障碍赛马大赛，但就在比赛前不久，它的一只蹄踵受了伤。
He was retired soon after, but his public life and fame by no means decreased with the end of his career.
不久后它便退役了，但它的公开活动和名气丝毫没有随着赛马生涯的结束而减退。
Red Rum traveled all over the country for various engagements.
红朗姆跑遍全国各地，应邀出席各种活动。
He often led pre-race parades at Aintree Racecourse and was a popular guest at charity benefits and public events.
它经常在安特里赛马场带领赛前巡场，也是慈善募捐活动和公共活动上受欢迎的嘉宾。